[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
“The mysterious unknown.”
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
[Kiriko] Alright! We’ll now take you
straight to the site of the exam.
Oh, wow! Isn’t it incredible
that we all passed?
[Kurapika] I wouldn’t celebrate just yet.
We’ve merely earned the right
to take the Exam.
[Leorio] It’s progress!
I say that calls for a little celebration!
RIVALS x FOR x SURVIVAL
ZABAN CITY
[narrator]
With the help of the Kiriko Navigators,
Gon and his new friends
arrive in Zaban City
the location of this year’s Hunter Exam.
A Navigator’s main job is to identify
worthy applicants for the Hunter Exam.
We’re also responsible
for guiding them to the Exam site.
You see,
that’s because it’s almost impossible
to find the location
without a Navigator.
[shopkeeper] Who wants a taste?
It’s Zaban’s world famous panda-frog
on a stick!
A delicacy!
This brooch here was excavated
from Zaban’s underground palace.
It’s a real find.
You know Zaban City
is one shady place.
[Kurapika]
A city that’s as prosperous as this one
is bound to attract its share
of unsavory characters.
Wow!
What do you think you’re doing, Gon?
Let’s go!
Right!
[man] Here we are.
I’m pretty sure that’s the building.
Whoa...
[Gon] It’s so tall!
Wow, what a nice place!
[Leorio] So that’s the Exam site, huh?
And this is the crowd that it draws.
Hunter applicants
from all across the world
congregate here.
My first shot at the Hunter Exam.
I wonder if this is how Dad felt!
[Kiriko son] Hey, guys!
-Over here.
-[all three] Huh?
This is it.
GOHAN
[Leorio]
Come on, you’re messing with us, right?
It just looks like a regular restaurant.
You’re tellin’ me that Hunter applicants
from all over the globe
come to this old dive to take the Exam?
That’s exactly right.
[all three] Huh?
[man] The Hunter Exam attracts
millions of applicants every year.
And no one would expect the Exam
to be held here, right?
[Leorio] Good point.
Welcome! Take a seat!
[man] Is the back room available?
What are you having?
The steak combo, please.
The one that’ll make us see the light.
Make it three.
Combo for three, eh?
How do you want ‘em cooked?
Grilled slowly over a low flame
‘til done, please.
Got it. See yourselves to the back room.
[Gon] Mmm...
[man] Okay, wait here.
[Leorio] For what?
Where are all the other applicants
-[Gon] I can’t wait for that steak combo!
-[Leorio chuckles]
Gon, that was just the password
to get us inside.
There’s no steak combo.
Okay.
So, we don’t get to eat?
[Kiriko son] Only one in ten thousand.
You’re very lucky.
That’s how many ever make it this far.
Nice job.
You did great for first-timers.
Well. Good luck to you.
Thanks for your help!
I hope that next year,
I can help you again.
[bang]
[Leorio] Whoa!
It seems this room
is actually an elevator.
That explains it.
That bastard thinks
he’ll see us again next year
because he expects us to fail!
[Kurapika] Once every three years.
What's that?
It’s how often a rookie passes the Exam.
[Gon] It’s that unusual?
It is.
Some can’t handle it.
It’s too mentally and physically taxing.
It’s also not too uncommon
for veterans to break the rookies so badly
that they never retake the test.
So that’s why people
who want to be Hunters
are willing to risk everything for it.
You’ve hit the nail right on the head,
my little friend!
Being a Hunter means making
more money than anyone in the world!
[Kurapika] Wrong!
People become Hunters
to join the world’s most noble profession!
Shut up, goody-goody!
Selfish money grubber!
[Kurapika growls]
Hey, Gon! Listen up!
There’s a list of the hundred
richest people every year
and every single year, there are
over fifty Hunters who make the list.
That’s more than half!
There are some Hunters, sad to say,
who seek treasure and wild game.
But they’re second rate.
True Hunters work tirelessly
to maintain order
in society as well as in nature!
Oh, screw that!
Once you’re a Hunter,
it’s free to enter most countries!
And facilities? No charge!
How’s that for benefits, huh?
Hunters have many difficult
and important responsibilities
preserving artifacts and species,
catching crooks
and even apprehending rogue Hunters.
It’s the fame and fortune!
That’s why people want to become Hunters!
No, it’s conviction, profound knowledge,
and a sound mind and body!
Traits that are a true Hunter’s pride!
[both growling]
[both] Hey, Gon! Which of us
do you agree with?
[both] What kind of Hunter will you be?
Well, when you put it that way,
I guess I...
[elevator dings]
[Kurapika] I think we’ve arrived.
[Leorio] We’ll finish this later.
[sighs with relief]
Is it me or is the mood here pretty grim?
We saw plenty of other applicants
in the city
but these guys’re different.
Each one of them
is a master in their own right.
‘Scuse me!
Looks like everybody’s really on edge
down here.
[Beans] Hello!
Please take your number badge. Thank you!
[Beans] Here you go!
Here.
Be sure to wear this on your chest
at all times, please.
And be careful not to lose it, okay?
[Tonpa]
Don’t think I’ve seen you boys before!
Yo!
You can tell it’s our first time here?
[Tonpa] More or less.
[grunts]
It’s getting easier.
It’s my thirty-fifth attempt,
so it comes with the territory.
[all three]
You’ve tried thirty-five times?
I guess you could say
I’m a Hunter Exam veteran.
Not really something to brag about.
Indeed.
Anyway, if you have any more questions,
I’d be happy to help.
Thanks a lot!
Oh, by the way, the name’s Tonpa.
Hi, I’m Gon.
This is Kurapika and this is Leorio.
You sure have taken the Exam a lot.
Are you the only one here
who’s tried a bunch of times
or are there others?
I might hold the record,
but yeah, there are others.
For instance…
That guy over there.
Number 255.
Todo, the wrestler.
Probably the strongest one here.
And he’s smarter than he looks.
Over there is 103.
Bourbon, the snake charmer.
He can really hold a grudge,
so try not to get on his bad side.
-[snake hisses]
-[Tonpa] Let’s see now...
Number 191, Bodoro,
the kung fu master.
He’s getting old, but he’s still
the best martial artist around.
Then there are the brothers,
Amori, Imori, and Umori.
They work great as a team,
so they almost always do really well.
And 384.
Geretta, the huntsman.
He specializes
in killing all kinds of creatures
with his blow dart and club.
There are more, but they’ve taken the Exam
the most times.
Oh, wow!
[screaming]
[strangled cries of pain]
My. How unusual.
Seems this poor man’s arms
have turned into flower petals.
Now you see them, now you don’t.
[gasps]
You should be more careful.
And do apologize if you bump into someone.
[murmuring]
Just perfect.
The psychopath is back again.
You know that guy?
So, does that mean he tried last year?
Number 44, Hisoka, the magician.
He was the number one pick
to pass last year’s Exam
until he almost killed an Examiner
he didn’t approve of.
Then what the hell is he doing here?!
They’re letting him
retake the Exam after something like that?
Of course, they are.
They change the content and Examiners
every year.
And the Examiners choose the new material.
The devil himself
could pass the Hunter Exam
-if the Examiners say it’s okay.
-[evil laughter]
It’s how the whole thing works.
Anyway, nobody likes the guy.
I’d keep my distance if I were you.
Well, he definitely looks dangerous.
Oh! I almost forgot!
Let’s have a toast to friendship.
Whaddya say?
Hey, thanks! Yeah, don’t mind if I do!
I was dying of thirst.
Thanks a lot, buddy!
Yeah, thanks a lot!
Thank you.
[examinee]
[chuckles] Well, there he goes.
Playing the nice guy again,
even though he’s the nastiest one here.
[examinee] Tonpa, the Rookie Crusher
[Tonpa]
Here’s to new friends and good fortune.
Cheers!
[chuckles] Sorry, guys.
But the juice I gave you
contains a powerful laxative.
One sip and your guts will be
on non-stop roller coaster for three days.
If you want to take the Exam,
I hope you brought plenty of diapers.
[chuckling]
HUNTER GLOSSARY
LEORIO
[sinister chuckle]
Huh?
I think this juice might’ve gone bad,
Mr. Tonpa.
It tastes funny.
Seriously?
That was a close call!
Huh? That’s odd.
Real sorry ‘bout that, fellas!
Impossible.
That laxative is flavorless and odorless!
Please forgive me!
I had no idea the juice was bad!
[Gon] You don’t have to apologize.
What about you? Is your stomach okay?
I’m all right. I’m totally fine!
Oh, good!
I’ve tried all kinds of plants and grasses
on the mountain back home.
So, I can usually taste
when something’s bad.
That’s some talent you got there!
[nervous chuckle]
Never seen anything like it!
Damn it! He just had to be
some wild mountain kid.
Sorry again.
I’ll see you boys around!
Man, I thought he would never shut up.
[Tonpa] Something isn’t quite right
about the crop of rookies this year.
Like 294. Hanzo.
The first time I talked to him,
he actually seemed pretty gullible.
Keep this to yourself.
But I am a ninja!
Oh! Is that so?
I seek the legendary scroll. Shhh!
It is my secret mission
to track down the Ultimate Ninja Scroll.
That’s why I’m becoming a Hunter.
Rumor has it that it’s hidden somewhere
that’s inaccessible to ordinary people.
Anyway, this place is pretty boring, huh?
I guess so.
Hey, we should have a toast.
To friendship and good fortune, eh?
I am a seasoned ninja.
I make it a point never to drink anything
offered to me by another.
You understand?
Oh. Right! Gotcha.
[nervous laughter]
[Tonpa] I can tell he’s no idiot.
One wrong move and I could’ve been
in some serious trouble.
-[rattle]
-Huh?
[Tonpa] Speaking of trouble, there’s 301.
That guy just oozes danger.
I know one thing;
I’m not going anywhere near him.
Then there’s the one I really can’t stand.
187,
Nicholas.
Must’ve been tough
to make it this far, huh?
Not really.
Everything’s gone
exactly as my data predicted.
I used historical data
from past Hunter Exams
to calculate this year’s location.
It was really quite simple.
And frankly, rather boring.
Oh. Well, good.
Impressive work, there, kid.
The name’s Tonpa.
It’s real nice to meet you!
Tonpa, is it?
Ah! There you are.
This is your thirty-fifth attempt.
That’s the second highest number
of attempts by anyone!
But it says here
that you do hold the current record
for the most consecutive attempts
with 30.
That’s quite impressive!
Thank you! But it’s no big deal.
Whaddya say? Ya wanna toast to friendship?
But after thirty-five attempts
you have yet
to successfully pass the Exam.
And so, I assume you’re too focused
on your “other” objective.
Am I right, Tonpa the Rookie-Crusher?
Say what?!
Fear not. I won’t divulge my findings
with anyone else.
Consider it a prize
for your consecutive appearance record.
Farewell.
[growls]
[Tonpa] Just wait, you little bastard.
I’m the one who’s gonna break
that snotty nose of yours.
[Killua] Hey! Mr. Tonpa!
That juice was great. Got any more?
I don’t know if I’m just nervous
but I really am thirsty!
Oh! Of course!
What the hell?!
That laxative he drank
should have taken effect by now!
What’s up with this kid?
It’s only a laxative, but still…
If the kid drinks that much,
he could die of dehydration.
[Killua] Worried?
Well, don’t be. I’ll be fine.
I’ve trained for this.
Poisons don’t hurt me.
Impossible!
That kid was actually able to tell
what was in the juice?
But if he knew…
then why the hell did he drink it?
Number 99, Killua.
Damn. This year’s rookies
are completely insane.
[smirks]
But so what?
It just means crushing them
will be all the more satisfying.
[bell ringing]
[wall rumbles]
Huh?
I apologize for the delay.
Thank you for waiting.
The entry period for Hunter applicants
is officially closed.
So, with no further ado,
the Hunter Exam will now begin!
-[smirks]
-[grunts]
[smirks]
One final word of caution…
If you’re short on luck or ability,
keep in mind that
there’s a very real chance
you could end up seriously injured.
Death is another distinct possibility.
[determined grunt]
If you’re willing
to accept the risks involved,
I’ll ask you to follow me now.
But for the rest of you
kindly exit through the elevator
located behind you.
[theme music playing]
Right, then. Very well.
All 404 applicants
will now participate in Phase One.
Yeah, I didn’t think anybody
was gonna leave.
But I’d hoped a few
would duck out at least.
[Leorio] Whoa. What...?
[Gon] I think the people up front
have started running.
[Kurapika]
It’s because he’s picking up the pace.
How rude of me.
I neglected to introduce myself.
I am Satotz, your Examiner
for the First Phase of the Exam.
It’s my responsibility
to lead all of you to the Second Phase.
Second?
Whatever happened to the First?
The First Phase is already underway.
[murmuring]
The First Phase is quite simple.
All you have to do is follow me
to the Second Phase.
So, try to keep up.
Follow you? So that’s it?
There’s nothing else?
[Satotz] That’s right.
I cannot tell you where
or when you must arrive.
You need only to follow me.
I see how it is.
This Exam is weird.
Sounds a lot like
a basic endurance test to me.
That’s right up my alley.
Keep running, pal! I’m right behind ya!
[Kurapika] Not knowing how far
we’ll have to run is mentally stressful,
to say nothing of the physical strain.
This is a test of our mental fortitude
as well.
[narrator] And so amidst a sea
of warriors and villains,
the First Phase of the Exam begins.
One candidate is disqualified
before the test even gets under way,
bringing the total number
of Hunter applicants to 404.
[panting]
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time:
"Hope x and x Ambition."
-Time to go fishin’!
-[Killua] Yeah.